Moe Yokota

UX/UI Designer

lionmocchi@outlook.com|(778)317 - 2931|Vancouver, BC <u>Portfolio</u>|<u>LinkedIn</u>

SUMMARY

A UX Designer with a foundation in graphic design and computer science, currently pursuing a UI/UX Design Diploma at Cornerstone International Community College in Vancouver, BC. I have a strong ability for research and logical analytical thinking, which are crucial for user understanding. I am committed to being a problem-solver who can offer digital experiences that are not only functional and beautiful but also sustainable and emotionally fulfilling.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graphic Designer (Japan)

Hiyoshi Dermatology Clinic

November 2020

Established in 2008, Hiyoshi Dermatology Clinic has been caring for the skin health of over 3000 patients and has become a trusted name in dermatology in Hakodate, Hokkaido. With rapidly growing brand awareness, the clinic sought to renew their business card design to better convey their unique brand identity. Here's my design work.

- Discussed the current brand strategy with the clinic owners.
- Proposed three upgraded design concepts with mood boards and rough sketches.
- Designed a new business card using Adobe Illustrator, and followed up with the client, modifying the card design according to the client's requests and industry regulations.
- Responsible for the whole process, including ordering the printing services to a third-party company.

VOLUNTEER

UX Designer (Canada)

PressReader

From April 2024 To July 2024

Providing interactive, digital access to nearly 7,000 of the world's best newspapers and magazines, PressReader is one of the globally popular digital news distribution platforms with more than 12 million monthly active users. To respond to the drastic shift in media consumption behaviors among young users, my team offered various solution ideas to this company for targeting this demographic. Here's the slide deck from our final presentation.

- Collaborated with a marketing team to gain insights from their survey research.
- Conducted various research methods such as desk research, CSD matrix, and user interviews to understand the problem.
- Analyzed the research data and shared findings with other designers through Notion documents and a FigJam whiteboard.
- Created a user persona and crafted a solution idea with wireframes using Figma.
- Worked closely with other UX designers to develop each solution idea and organized all ideas into a comprehensible presentation using Canva.

Graphic Designer (Japan)

Sakura Onigiri Store

From November 2023 To January 2024

Sakura is a local food place in Hakodate, Hokkaido, known for selling onigiri (Japanese rice balls) with affordable price and fulfilling quality. Due to the opening of its second branch, the business wanted to redesign their product packaging to enhance brand recognition. Here's my design work.

- Communicated with the client to understand her personal design preferences and current business strategy.
- Conducted competitor research to study general market needs and trends.

- Proposed several brand renewal concepts with mood boards and rough sketches..
- Designed a paper bag and product packaging with three design variations using Adobe Illustrator.
- Revised the chosen design based on the client's request and industry regulations.
- Delivered the final design in PDF format to a third-party printer.

PROJECTS

Website Redesign for No Frills | June 2024

Redesigned the user experience of the e-commerce website for No Frills, one of Canada's major grocery brands, to enhance overall customer satisfaction.

- Contributed to project management by proposing the overall plan to the team leader and assisting in schedule adjustments.
- Conducted competitor research and UX pyramid evaluations with other designers.
- Built carousel and product card components for the team's UI kit.
- Organized the UI kit and refined some component designs.
- Created wireframes and prototypes for the category page.
- Assisted team members with Figma during the design process.
- Collaboratively set up a usability testing survey.

Tech Stack: Figma, Google Forms, Trello

Medical Appointment Web Application | May 2024

Designed a medical appointment platform providing easy access for users to get professional support for mental well-being, addressing the common mental health challenges faced by remote workers.

- Managed the fast-paced project schedule, adopting the design sprint structure.
- Communicated with teammates to share findings from individual desk research and to determine the specific problem and solution idea to focus on.
- Collaboratively worked on a storyboard and a low-fidelity wireframe using the Crazy 8 method.
- Created a scheduling page prototype, making sure the user has an enjoyable and easy to use experience.
- Structured the research process for guerrilla usability testing and assisted team members in refining their interviewing skills.

Tech Stack: Figma, Coda

SKILLS

Design Tools: Figma, Canva, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe XD

Research Tools: Optimal Workshop, Google Forms, Google Sheets, Microsoft Excel

Project Management Tools: Notion, Coda, Trello, Slack, Microsoft Teams

Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, Java, Python

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES

UI/UX Designer Advanced Co-op Diploma (Jan 2024 - Present)

Cornerstone International Community College, Vancouver, BC

Courses taken: Information Design, Multi-Platform UI Design, Design Evaluation, Design Communication, etc.

Bachelor of Studio Art (Graphic Design) (2022)

University of Redlands, Redlands, CA

Courses taken: Drawing, Digital Imaging, Typography, History of Graphic Design, Intermediate Graphic

Design

Bachelor of Computer Science (2022)

University of Redlands, Redlands, CA

Courses taken: Data, File Structures, and OOP, Theory of Algorithms, Database Management, Web Application Development, Statistics.